What's the difference between a video
that gets 5,000 views and one that gets
5 million views? It's probably the first
3 seconds. Everyone is a content creator
now, and the landscape has completely
changed in the past 12 months where even
regular business owners are now spending
tens of thousands of dollars on coaching
just to optimize their videos. So, if
your hooks are average or just okay,
you're going to get left behind in 2025.
Lucky for you, I've turned hooks into a
simple science. We've generated over 5
billion views for our clients. And
there's a common thread between the most
viral videos we've created that generate
a lot of lead flow regardless of
industry. And if you still aren't
convinced, we literally write three
unique hooks for every single short form
video that goes out for our clients on
all platforms. My team thought this was
crazy until they realized how important
this was for getting people results.
Today, I'm going to show you the
psychology behind why hooks work, the
exact hook formulas we use, and how you
can trap viewers into these crucial
first few seconds. So, there is a hook
crisis in 2025. And one of the biggest
things that you want to follow is the
3-second rule. See, your ideal customer
is scrolling through their feed at
lightning speed, and in the first 3
seconds, their brain makes a split
decision of is this worth my time or
not. If your hook doesn't immediately
grab them, they're gone forever. Most
people are making this decision in
milliseconds per piece of content. And
there's a few reasons why most business
owners get this wrong. See, most
approach hooks like writing a college
essay where they want to ease into the
topic, provide context, and introduce
themselves first. Say, "Hi, this is
Logan Foresight here. I'm X, Y, and Z."
And you immediately lose the attention
of the viewers. You should not do this.
See, if you have a weak hook, then the
viewer experience is in the first second
they're wondering, "What is this about?"
Second second, they're thinking, "This
seems boring." and then third second
they're swiping versus if you have a
strong hook the viewer experience in the
first second is wait what is this second
second is I need to know more and then
third second is all right I'm going to
watch this and they commit to watching
your video you see strong hooks create
something called cognitive tension where
the brain can't move on until it gets
the answer so there's important
psychology behind creating irresistible
hooks and one of the biggest pillars is
the curiosity gap see your brain hates
incomplete information and so when you
create a curiosity gap. That's a gap
between what you know and what you want
to know. The brain becomes obsessed with
filling that gap and great hooks exploit
this by promising valuable information
without revealing it immediately. A lot
of people make the mistake of giving
away the entire enchilada right up front
in the video of telling them the lesson
of the video or the lesson of the story
right at the start. You want to promise
valuable information, but don't reveal
the entire lesson immediately right up
front. And don't do this in your caption
as well. You want to create questions
that demand answers and you can hint at
surprising or counterintuitive
information. Another psychology pillar
of this is using pattern interrupts.
See, viewers are in a scrolling trance,
seeing similar content repeatedly, and
great hooks break that pattern and force
attention. Some easy examples are stop
doing this or everyone gets this wrong
and they interrupt the expected pattern
because they're going against the grain
of what everyone deems as acceptable on
this common topic or this relatable
topic. And the third big pillar is the
stakes framework. You see, every great
hook establishes stakes and answers what
happens if I don't watch this. So for
business owners, stakes might be missing
out on revenue, falling behind
competitors, or wasting money on
ineffective strategies. and you can
establish that upfront in your hook and
make them feel as if they don't watch
that video, they're more likely to
experience the consequences of those
common mistakes. Through this process,
we've identified five hook formulas that
consistently generate millions of views
but also translate into leads, sales,
revenue, and profit for your business
where we're not just chasing vanity
metrics. Formula one is the mistake
reveal. So the structure can be the
number one mistake that target audience
makes with common topic. So an example
is the number one mistake coaches make
with their content that's costing them
seven figures. Why this works is that
nobody wants to make expensive mistakes
and so this creates immediate urgency. A
business application of this could be a
marketing consultant could use the
number one mistake small businesses make
with Facebook ads that waste 80% of
their budget. The second hook formula is
the counterintuitive truth. See the
structure you can use for this is why
common belief is actually hurting your
desired outcome. So an example could be
why posting daily is actually killing
your engagement. And why this works is
it challenges what people think that
they know which creates cognitive
dissonance. A business application of
this could be a fitness coach that uses
the hook why doing cardio every day is
actually preventing you from losing
weight. Formula number three is the
transformation tease. And the structure
of this is how I went from bad situation
to good situation in X time frame. So,
an example would be how I went from 10
leads a month to 1,000 leads a month on
social media in 90 days. Why this works
is because people want transformation
and this promises a road map in a
specific time frame. So, a business
application of this for a real estate
agent could be how I went from two home
sales per year to 50 home sales per year
using this one strategy. The fourth hook
formula is the urgent warning. The
structure of this is stop doing
something before negative consequence
happens. So an example would be stop
using these hashtags before Instagram
shadowbans your account. Why this works
is because fear of loss is more powerful
than desire for gain. So another
business application of this could be an
accountant saying stop making these tax
mistakes before the IRS audits your
business. Hook formula number five is
the secret reveal. The structure of this
is number of secrets that this authority
figure doesn't want you to know. So an
example would be three YouTube secrets
Mr. beast doesn't want you to know. And
why this works is because everyone loves
insider information and it feels like
they're getting exclusive access. So, an
example business application of this for
a contractor could be five secrets home
improvement stores don't want you to
know about buying materials. So, now
here's a huge secret that nobody does,
nobody talks about. And having this can
be an ultimate edge for building your
brand on socials, and that is hook
testing. and why we write three
variations for every single hook that we
put together for the scripts for our
clients. We refer to this as the split
test strategy because hooks are the
highest leverage point in your entire
video. And the best video in the world
means nothing if the hook doesn't work.
It's like having the best product but
terrible packaging. And so how you can
actually test hooks in your organic
content that nobody else does is by
creating three variations using
different formulas that we're talking
about and then post them as separate
videos across sub accounts per platform.
You cannot do this if you only have one
main account per platform. If you only
have one Instagram account, one YouTube
channel, one Tik Tok, etc. You cannot
post three videos with three separate
hooks on that same account because the
same audience is going to be exposed to
those videos. But if you have sub
accounts, then you can do this. And so
instead of just having one account on
Instagram, go in and create two
additional sub accounts that are still
branded to you. An example we can use is
Tony Robbins. Instead of Tony Robbins
just having his main account at Tony
Robbins, he can also go in and create
additional sub accounts that are still
branded to him, such as Tony Robbins
talks, Tony Robbins reals, Tony Robbins
clips, so on and so forth. And having
that would allow him to then split test
hooks for every single video. Again, the
hook alone can be the difference between
a video getting 5 million views and
5,000 views. And this also 3xes your
output of every single video that you
create and produce and post on socials.
Therefore, giving you three at bats to
hit another viral home run compared to
just one per video and then crossing
your fingers hoping that it's going to
work. When you do this, you now actually
have much more data to go off of from
split testing the hooks to truly
understand what works the best. track
performance on all of this within the
first 24 to 72 hours. And then you want
to triple down on the hook formulas and
the topics that are working the best.
And if you have a proven hook on a sub
account, you can always then post that
same hook and video on your main account
as well, which is going to drive more
performance there. The sub accounts can
also all funnel back to your main
socials by having your main account
tagged in the post and the content in
the captions as pin comments. You can
have your main handle in the bio of the
accounts. There's a lot of different
ways to funnel this traffic back. Now,
this truly is some sauce. And this truly
is one of the biggest formulas to win on
social media today. And if it sounds
like a lot, I get it. And if you want a
team to do this for you, this is exactly
what we do for all of our clients. We're
very specific about who we work with
because we only want to create top level
case studies and have very long
relationships with clients and know with
100% confidence that we're going to win
when going into a relationship. The way
we work, we put a lot of skin in the
game with each of our clients by working
largely performance-based and then we
guarantee satisfaction and results where
if we don't win for you, we don't make
any profit and we can actually lose
money and lose opportunity as part of
the partnership. This works specifically
if you are a business that's doing
minimum 3 million per year in revenue
and you have a focus on content and
scaling your brand on socials. If that's
you, check out the description below and
you can apply to work with us. And we
also have a full training video showing
you exactly how all this works. So,
let's go through some bad hook versus
good hook examples. So, bad hook
examples could be, "Hey everyone,
welcome back to my channel. Today, I
want to talk about marketing strategies.
Why this is bad is because it has no
urgency, no curiosity, and no stakes."
Another bad hook example is in this
video I'm going to show you some tips
for growing your business. Why this is
bad is because it's vague. It has no
specific benefit and it sounds generic.
Another bad example is let me introduce
myself and tell you about my company.
Why this is bad is because it makes it
about you and not your viewers problems.
So now let's get into some good hook
examples. A good hook could be this one
email template generated 2.3 million in
revenue for my client. Why this works is
because it's a specific number. It
promises value through a template and it
creates curiosity. Another good hook can
be, "I analyzed 1,000 failed businesses
and found that they all made the same
three mistakes." Why this works is
because it creates authority, promises
to help avoid failure, and provide
specific numbers. Another good hook
example is the marketing strategy that
Coca-Cola uses, but won't teach you. And
why this works is because it leverages
an authority figure, has secret
information, and therefore has
exclusivity. Now, with all that said,
hooks aren't only what you say, they're
also what viewers see. And so therefore,
we have visual hooks as well. And visual
hooks can be just as powerful as verbal
hooks. And sometimes the visual is the
hook before you even speak in a video.
So a few of the top visual hook
strategies that we use are pattern
interrupts where something visually
unexpected happens in the first frame.
You have high energy moments where you
have action, movement or dramatic
gestures. You can use props and objects
which are physical items that create
curiosity. You can have location changes
which are unique or interesting
backgrounds. Text overlays also can
crush it, which are bold statements that
complement your verbal hook. So, a
visual hook for a business coach could
be filming content in your PJ or maybe
you're filming in a nice area with a big
room behind you to have big spaces. You
need to generally have more wealth.
Posting content of you speaking on stage
or a bunch of people watching you and
asking you questions. All of these
showcase subtle visual cues that you are
an authority and therefore someone that
people should listen to on socials. A
visual hook for an agency could be
showing multiple videos going viral. A
video hook for a fitness coach could be
before and after transformation photos
as you speak. For a restaurant, it could
be a close-up of an incredible dish
that's being prepared. And then the most
powerful hooks combine strong verbal and
visual elements together. The visual
grabs the attention and then the verbal
hook keeps them watching. You can think
of the visual as the thumbnail in motion
for your video. And the first frame
should be as compelling as your first
words. And now let's get into some
advanced hook psychology. And first we
can start with the specificity
principle. You see, specific numbers and
details make hooks more believable and
compelling. So if you compare a vague
hook of how to make a lot of money to a
specific hook of how to make $1 million
per month, the specific version creates
a clearer picture and feels more
achievable and desirable and also speaks
much more direct and specific to the
person that you want to be speaking to
and attracting for your content. Next,
we have the authority transfer, which is
where you're mentioning recognizable
names or companies and it borrows their
authority for your content. A great
example is the Coca-Cola marketing
secrets that they don't want you to know
hook example that I gave you earlier.
Next is we have the time constraint. So
adding time elements creates more
urgency in your hooks. So you could
start by saying in the next 60 seconds
or before 2025 or this week only. And
what this does is it taps into fear of
missing out and creates immediate
action. So, let's tie this together and
give you some actionable takeaways and
create a hook checklist. So, before
publishing your next video, create this
checklist and ask yourself, does my hook
create curiosity or high emotion? Are
there stakes? What happens if they don't
watch? Is it specific? Make promises
don't work? Does it pattern interrupt?
Does it stand out? And can I make it
more urgent? As another action step and
exercise, you can go out there and find
hook inspiration for your content and
study other industries and see what's
working. So much of the time you can
apply those same content types and
frameworks to your industry. And if you
are a first mover on that proven content
from a different space that applies it
to your space, many times it'll crush
there as well. This doesn't just apply
to content. This applies to business
strategy in general. And a lot of people
pigeon hole themselves by only looking
at their industry alone. But I digress.
You want to go out there and find at
least 50 high engagement videos. And the
more of this you do, the better you're
going to get. To keep it simple with
this, you can use Tik Tok search, which
is the top search engine platform for
short form video content. And you can
also use a Google Chrome extension
called Sortfeed, which will sort the top
ranking and top performing content for
specific accounts on Instagram and Tik
Tok. All you need to do is grab a cup of
coffee, block out 3, four hours, and
then go through this process. Find those
videos, write down their hooks on a
Google or Excel sheet, and then look for
patterns and formulas to create your
swipe file for future hook inspiration
that you use as well. Now, if you run a
business doing over 3 million per year
and you want our team to handle your
entire content strategy and just manage
everything for you, including writing
the scripts, coming up with a content
strategy, using those three hook
variations per video, taking ownership
over all of the lead genen and
conversion that comes from your socials,
working with only top level talent as
social media experts, top level quality
editing, and only working with the best
for your team of social media experts,
the managers, top quality quality
editing, the graphic design that we put
in, and overall taking the approach
where we can fully script out videos for
you, have three hook variations. Every
single script includes CTAs to drive
lead genen and therefore sales for your
business while also tapping into the
most growth that you've ever seen on
your socials. Doing this with
performance-based pricing and
satisfaction guaranteed, where we put
skin in the game with you, and overall
coming in with the systems and the team
where all you have to do is film less
than 2 hours per month. Our team will
handle the rest and post over 420 times
per month for you minimum. And we can go
much higher to thousands of posts per
month and drive more results than you've
ever seen. And if you want to learn how
we've generated over 1 million organic
leads from social media with our
clients, check out the video that you
see right here. Thanks for watching and
I'll see you in the next video.